Lou Blachly papers, 1827-1965
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
Papers of Lou Blachly, 1827-1965
MS 083
Blachly, Lou
Includes correspondence, reports, manuscripts, diaries, photographs, poetry, souvenir ephemera, and newspapers of the Bradley and Blachly families.
30 linear feet
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
Restrictions
There are no restrictions on this collection.
Biographical Note
Louis Blachly, son of Andrew True Blachly and Adelle Bradley Blachly, was born on November 5, 1889 in Delta Colorado. Blachly was active in high school but was unable to earn his diploma due to illness. He was, however, accepted to Oberlin College in 1911. He was forced to leave Oberlin that same year because of family responsibilities but in 1912 he was able to continue his education at the University of Wisconsin in Madison. This was again disrupted by family obligations however Blachly finally earned an A.B. in economics in 1919.
In 1922 Blachly married Natalie Norton and they had two children. Blachly worked for several departments of the Federal Government including the War Department, the Executive Office of the President, Office of Price Administration, the Executive Office of the President, Office of Emergency Management, the Foreign Economic Administration and the Department of State. This required that the family move frequently and involved considerable time overseas. This resulted in a strained marriage and Blachly and Natalie divorced in 1947.
In 1951 Blachly solicited support from prominent businessmen in Silver City, New Mexico in order to form the Pioneer Foundation. This organization was dedicated to recording reminiscences of the remaining “pioneers” of New Mexico and the Southwest.
In 1957 Blachly moved to Tucson, Arizona. He published two books, Picture Guide to Southwestern Arizona Wildflowers (1963) and Mammals, Snakes, and Lizards of the Southwest (1964). He died at home on March 5, 1965. His remains were cremated and scattered in the desert near Tucson.
Organization
This collection is divided into Fifteen series. The papers were processed in 1967. The first 290 Oral History recordings, including reel 598, were duplicated, preserved and processed in 2002.
Series I: Family History. circa 1827-1965
Series II: Dan B. Bradley, Photographs of Siam and Bradley Family. 1834-187)
Series III: Books Owned by Lou Blachly. Undated
Series IV: Family Correspondence. 1836-1965
Series V: Lou Blachly’s Manuscript on His Mother’s Life. Undated
Series VI: Family Reminiscences. 1942-1964
Series VII: Various Correspondence. 1923-1965
Series VIII: Government Service. 1941-1949
Series IX: Articles authored by Lou Blachly on the World Situation. Undated
Series X: Pioneers Foundation, 1950-1965
Series XI: Nature Writings, 1948-1964
Series XII: Miscellaneous Personal Materials, 1943-1946
Series XIII: Poetry and Music authored by Lou Blachly. 1917-1964
Series XIV: Diaries, 1920-1965
Series XV: Oversize Materials and newspapers, 1893-1947
Series XVI: Oral History Recordings
Scope and Content Note
Includes correspondence, reports, manuscripts, diaries, photographs, poetry, souvenir ephemera, and newspapers. General family history includes typescripts of biographical notes, correspondence, and remembrances by various members of both the Bradley and Blachly families. Photocopied materials of Dan Beach Bradley's mission work in Siam include a typescript of his journal describing medical practices. Correspondence is both between missions and with the King of Siam. Photographs depict the family, their house, village scenes, temples, and the royalty.
Lou Blachly's government service files relate to provisioning of food, farm machinery, and other supplies to North Africa; and economic issues of German reconstruction, including brief descriptions and photographs of conditions. Ephemera encompasses various foreign currencies, U.S. War Dept. pamphlets, and Nazi materials. Typescripts of Blachly's published and unpublished writings include his diaries from 1920 to 1965; poems; musical compositions; the story about his mother, Mary Adelle Blachly, and her pioneer life in Colorado; versions of his book Naming Birds at a Glance, and articles on bird and wild flower identification. His work with the Pioneers Foundation resulted in records, correspondence, transcripts and oral history tapes relating to New Mexico settlers and pioneers, including Montague Stevens.
Some items in French, German, and Siamese.
Access Terms
Blachly, Lou -- Archives
Bradley, Dan Beach -- 1804-1873
Stevens, Montague -- 1859-1953 -- Interviews
Blachly, Mary Adelle -- 1854-1926
Blachly family -- Genealogy
Bradley family -- Genealogy
United States -- Foreign Economic Administration
Pioneers Foundation (New Mexico)
Frontier and pioneer life -- Colorado
Frontier and pioneer life -- New Mexico
Women pioneers -- Colorado
Missions, Medical -- Thailand -- History -- 19th century
Reconstruction (1939-1951) -- Africa, North
Reconstruction (1939-1951) -- Germany
Wild flowers -- Arizona
Bird watching -- United States -- Guidebooks
Birds -- United States
World War, 1939-1945 -- Food supply
World War, 1939-1945 -- Economic aspects -- Africa, North
World War, 1939-1945 -- Economic aspects -- Germany
World War, 1939-1945 -- Destruction and pillage -- Germany
Germany -- Economic conditions--1945-1990
Germany -- History -- 1945-1955
Thailand
Correspondence
Diaries
Photographs
Reports
Oral Histories
Container List
- Series I: Family History, 1927-1965
  Contains correspondence regarding family history, notes, bibliographies, photographs and miscellaneous materials.
  - Lou Blachly: Correspondence Regarding Family History, 1937-1965 (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
  - The Families of Thomas Blachly and William Bradley compiled by Clarence Blachly, 1827-1965 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Blachly Family (Miscellaneous Notes, Biographies, etc.,) 1827-1965 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Bradley Family (Miscellaneous Notes, Biographies, etc.,) 1827-1965 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Andrew Trew Blachly (Miscellaneous Material,) 1827-1965 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Charles Grandison Finney (Biographical Material,) 1827-1965 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Cornelius B. Bradley (Biographical Material,) 1827-1965 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Account Book Kept by Mary Adelle Blachly, 1909-1917 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Delta, Colorado (Photographs,) 1827-1965 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Delta, Colorado (Photographs,) 1827-1965 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Series II: Dan B. Bradley Papers, 1836-1967
  Contains materials relating to Dan B. Bradley’s (Blachly’s maternal grandfather) medical missionary work in Siam (now Thailand). This series includes correspondence, journal abstracts, diary excerpts, photographs, calendars and family reminiscences of Siam. There are also two scrapbooks and several books relating to Siam.
  - D.B. Bradley (Correspondence,) 1835-1886 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - D.B. Bradley (Miscellaneous Materials,) 1827-1965 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - D.B. Bradley (Abstract of Journal,) 1835-1872 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Emilie (Royce) Bradley (Excerpts from Diary,) 1834-1836 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Emilie (Royce) Bradley (Drafts of Letters,) 1835-1836 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - King of Siam (Correspondence and Miscellaneous Papers,) 1827-1965 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Bangkok Calendar, 1849, 1863, 1865-1866, 1868, 1870-1872 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Siam (Miscellaneous Material), 1835-1872 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Photographs (Siam, Bradley Family, etc.,) 1835-1872 (Box 2, type="folder">9)
  - Family Reminiscences of Siam, 1835-1872 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Photographs of Siam and Bradley Family. (Includes 2 scrapbooks, 1835-1872 (Box 3)
  - Books (Box 4)
    Starling, Lucy, Dawn Over Temple Roofs, NY, World Horizons, 1960
    Steidenfaden, Erik,Guide to Bangkok, with notes on Siam, 2nd ed., Royal State Railways of Siam, 1928
    Wells, Kenneth E., History of Protestant Work in Thailand 1828-1958, Church of Christ, Bangkok, Thailand, 1958
    Bradley, Ruth,Dellie: A Lotus in the Dust, Ber-Cal Publishing Company, Berkley, California, 1967
- Series III: Family Correspondences, 1936-1965
  - Sarah (Blachly) Bradley (Correspondence: General,) 1836-1893 (Box 5, Folder 1-3)
  - Sarah (Blachly) Bradley (Correspondence: D.B. Bradley,) 1848-1849, 1857-1858 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Adelle (Bradley) Blachly (Correspondence,) 1866-1893 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Dwight Bradley (Correspondence), 1870-1875 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Dan Freeman Bradley (Correspondence), 1871-1892 (Box 5, Folder 7-8)
  - Adelle (Bradley) Blachly (Photographs), 1836-1893 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Series IV: Lou Blachly’s Manuscripts on His Mother’s Life. 1877-1915
  Contains an outline, introduction, reports, expenses and twenty chapters from a bibliographic manuscript chronically the life of Lou Blachly’s mother
  - L.B.'s Manuscript on His Mother's Life: Outline, Contents, Introduction, undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - L.B.'s Manuscript on His Mother's Life: Chapter I "September 5, 1877." Chapter II "Monument," undated (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - L.B.'s Manuscript on His Mother's Life: Chapters III-VIII "Bangkok," " Salida, Colo.," " Gunnison, Colo.," and "Indians," undated (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - L.B.'s Manuscript on His Mother's Life: Chapter IX "Virgin land I (Oak Creek)," udated (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - L.B.'s Manuscript on His Mother's Life: Chapter X "Brief Interlude," undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - L.B.'s Manuscript on His Mother's Life: Chapter XI, "September 7, 1893." (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - L.B.'s Manuscript on His Mother's Life: Chapter XII "Virgin Land II (Garnet Mesa)," udated (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - L.B.'s Manuscript on His Mother's Life: Chapter XIII "Getting a Toe Hold;" Chapter XIV "Wild and Free, undated (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - L.B.'s Manuscript on His Mother's Life: Chapter XV "School Days;" Chapter XVI "Peach Valley," undated (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - L.B.'s Manuscript on His Mother's Life: Chapter XVII "Blachly Brothers Cattle Co.;" Chapter XVIII "By the Skin of Your Teeth, undated (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - L.B.'s Manuscript on His Mother's Life: Chapter XIX "September 8, 1915;" Chapter XX "War and Wanderings, undated (Box 6, Folder 11)
- Series V: Family reminiscences, 1942-1964
  - L.B.: Recollections (Various Tape Transcripts), undated (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - L.B.: Recollections (Transcripts of Tapes No. 2, 5-10), undated (Box 7, Folder 2-3)
  - L.B.: Childhood Reminiscences - Melvale Farm, undated (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - L.B.: Childhood Reminiscences - November 20, 1942 (original and typescript), undated (Box 7, Folder 5-6)
  - L.B.: Child Reminiscences - Return, 1953 (original and typescript), undated (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Ralph Blachly, (Tape Typescript,) 1964 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Fred Blachly, (Tape Typescript). August 20, 1963 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Mrs. Taylor B. Greer, (Tape Typescript), September 7, 1953 (Box 7, Folder 10)
- Series VI: Various Correspondence, 1923-1965
  - Mary Adelle (Bradley) Blachly (Various Correspondence). 1900-1926 (Box 8, Folder 1-2)
  - Mary Adelle (Bradley)Blachly (Correspondence with Lou). 1915-1926 (Box 8, Folder 3-4)
  - Clarence "Dan" Blachly (Correspondence). 1920-1965 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Edward Blachly (Correspondence,) 1920-1965 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Fred Blachly (Correspondence,) 1898-1964 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Howard Blachly (Correspondence); Hal Blachly (Photograph Only,) 1917-1926 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Ralph Blachly (Correspondence) 1940-1964 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    Some photographs included in above folders.
  - Correspondence: Lou to Natalie, 1922-1962 (Box 9, Folder 1-6)
  - Correspondence: Lou to Family (North Africa, Middle East). 1943-1944 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence: Lou and Bill (Son), 1942-1945 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence: Lou and Barbara (Daughter), 1930?-1964 (Box 9, Folder 9-10)
    Note: Photographs included in some folders.
  - Correspondence: Miscellaneous, 1923 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: Miscellaneous, 1940s (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: Miscellaneous, 1950s (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: Miscellaneous, 1960s (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: Food Brokerage and Export Business, 1937-1942 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: George T. Bye, 1941-1955 (Box 10, type="folder">6)
  - Correspondence: Harold Bradley; Ruth Bradley (Also Some Articles,) 1952-1965; 1962-1964 (Box 10, Folder 7)
- Series VII: Government Service, 1941-1945
  - War Department (Quartermaster Market Center, Columbia, SC): L. Blachly Personal Papers, April 1941-June 1942 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - War Department (Quartermaster Market Center, Columbia, SC): Instructions and Procedures, 1941 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - War Department (Quartermaster Market Center, Columbia, SC): Miscellaneous Papers, undated (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Office of Price Administration (Washington, DC,) September 1942-March 1943 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Foreign Economic Administration (North Africa): L. Blachly Personal Papers, March 1943-March 1945 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Foreign Economic Administration (North Africa): L. Blachly Notebooks, undated (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Foreign Economic Administration (North Africa): General Administrative Papers, 1943-1945 (Box 12, type="folder">1)
  - Foreign Economic Administration (North Africa): Meetings and Reports, 1943-1945 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Foreign Economic Administration (North Africa): Food Production, 1943-1945 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Foreign Economic Administration (North Africa): Food Rations and Requirements, 1943-1945 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Foreign Economic Administration (North Africa): Farm Machinery. 1943-1945 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Foreign Economic Administration (North Africa): Fats and Oils, 1943-1945 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Foreign Economic Administration (North Africa): Fertilizers, 1943-1945 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Foreign Economic Administration (North Africa): Fruits and Vegetables, 1943-1945 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Foreign Economic Administration (North Africa): Grain, 1943-1945 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Foreign Economic Administration (North Africa): Locusts, 1943-1945 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Foreign Economic Administration (North Africa): Diary, 1943-1945 (Box 13, Folder 1-2)
  - Foreign Economic Administration (North Africa): Miscellaneous Notes, 1943-1945 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Foreign Economic Administration (North Africa): Music, 1943-1945 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Foreign Economic Administration (North Africa): Poetry, 1943-1945 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Foreign Economic Administration (North Africa): Sketches and Paintings, 1943-1945 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Foreign Economic Administration (North Africa): Photographs I - Tunisia, Morocco, Algeria, 1943-1945 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Foreign Economic Administration (North Africa): Photographs II - Lou Blachly and Staff of North African Economic Mission; Arab Groups and Stree Scenes; Potato Aid; Water and Irrigation; Agricultural Photographs; Unidentified, 1943-1945 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Foreign Economic Administration (North Africa): General Background Material, 1943-1945 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Foreign Economic Administration (North Africa): Agriculture Background Material, 1943-1945 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Foreign Economic Administration (North Africa): Background Material on Algeria, 1943-1945 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Foreign Economic Administration: Palestine and Iran. 1943-1945 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Foreign Economic Administration: Italy, 1943-1945 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Foreign Economic Administration: Washington, DC - Food Relief for Canada and United Kingdom, 1943-1945 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - (Box 14, 7)
    Includes: Final Report on Foreign Aid of the House Select Committee on Foreign Aid, pursuant to H.Res. 296, 1948.
  - War Department: Military Government, Germany - L. Blachly Personal Papers, 1946-1948 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - War Department: Military Government, Germany - Miscellaneous Notes, Worksheets, 1946-1948 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - War Department: Military Government, Germany- Notebooks, 1946-1948 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - War Department: Military Government, Germany - Personal Mementos and Souvenirs; Bills, 1946-1948 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - War Department: Military Government, Germany - Autobiography (Made Up of Diary, Letters, Poems), 1945-1946 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - War Department: Military Government, Germany - Agriculture, Food, Forestry, 1945-1946 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - War Department: Military Government, Germany - Fuel, 1945-1947 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - War Department: Military Government, Germany - Production and Export/Import Plan, 1947-1948 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - War Department: Military Government, Germany - Dismantling, January 1947-July 1948 (Box 16, Folder 4-5)
  - War Department: Military Government, Germany - General Transport, 1946-1947 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - War Department: Military Government, Germany - Auto Transport, 1946-1947 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - War Department: Military Government, Germany - Rail Transport, 1946-1947 (Box 16, Folder 8-9)
  - War Department: Military Government, Germany - Supplies for Reichsbahn, 1947 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - War Department: Military Government, Germany - Water, 1945-1947 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - War Department: Military Government, Germany - Diary, 1945-1948 (Box 17, Folder 1-3)
  - War Department: Military Government, Germany - Poetry, p. 1-81. Also Some German Translations of L.B.'s Poems, 1945-1947 (Box 17, Folder 4-6)
  - War Department: Military Government, Germany - Poetry, 1945-1948 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - War Department: Military Government, Germany - Photographs. Personal, Various Subjects. Lou Blachly & Family, Refugees (Berlin),Bridge Destruction & Rebuilding, Factories & Factory Workers, Friends of L.B., Returning of S.S. Prisoners, Bomb Destruction (unidentified cities), Wood Gathering (Berlin and Grunewald), 1946-1948 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - War Department: Military Government, Germany - Photographs. Berlin, 1946-1948 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - War Department: Military Government, Germany - Photographs Frankfurt and Munich, 1946-1948 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - War Department: Military Government, Germany - Photographs. Bavaria, Miscellaneous, Berchtesgaden, 1946-1948 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - War Department: Military Government, Germany - Photographs. Various Towns. Herford & Surrounding Countryside, Nuremberg, Kassel, Stuttgart, Heidelberg, 1946-1948 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - War Department: Military Government, France - Photographs. Paris, Vitrolles, Marseilles, Southern France, 1946-1948 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - War Department: Military Government, Germany - Photographs. Switzerland, Spain, 1946-1948 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - War Department: Military Government, Germany - Lou Blachly's Drawings and Sketches, 1946-1948 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - War Department: Military Government, Germany - Background Material and Publications on Berlin Airlift; Strategic Bombing, 1946-1948 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - War Department: Military Government, Germany - Background Material and Publications on Control Commission for Germany (British Element, Berlin, 1946-1948 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - War Department: Military Government, Germany - Background Material and Publications on Economic Cooperation Administration, 1946-1948 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - War Department: Military Government, Germany - Background Material and Publications on Food and Agriculture, U.S. and U.K. Zones, 1946-1948 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - War Department: Military Government, Germany - Background Material and Publications on Office of Military Government for Germany (U.S.), 1946-1948 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - War Department: Military Government, Germany - Background Material and Publications on Reconstruction, Relief, Rehabilitation, 1946-1948 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - War Department: Military Government, Germany - Background Material and Publications on Reconstruction Plan, 1948-1949 (Box 19, Folder 7)
- Articles authored by Lou Blachy on the World Situation
  - Article by L.B.: "American Free Enterprise in Germany," 1946-1948 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Article by L.B.: "Creating an Independent Commission on Peace," 1946-1948 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Article by L.B.: Draft of a Proposed Telegram to the President of the U.S., 1946-1948 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Article by L.B.: "Keep the Hate Fires Burning," 1946-1948 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Article by L.B.: "Not Enough Wheels," 1946-1948 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Article by L.B.: "Cold War to Blood War" Originally "Called Two Professors in Germany," 1946-1948 (Box 20, Folder 6-8)
  - Miscellaneous Articles and Notes.: "A Memo on Peace," "When Do We Eat?," " Overgrazing in North Africa and Iran," " Food Situation in the Mediterranean Area," " Battleground of the War Against Hunger," " Let's Get Out," "An Open Letter to the People of the United States" (courtesy of the Reader's Digest), "You Asked for It," and "World Peace," 1944-1948 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Radio and Ogranization Talks, 1945, 1948 (Box 20, Folder 10)
- Series IX: Pioneers Foundation, Inc., 1950-1965
  - Pioneers Foundation, Inc.: General Correspondence, 1950-1956, 1960-1965 (Box 21, Folder 1-7)
  - Pioneers Foundation, Inc.: Correspondence (Maurice G. Fulton), 1932, 1952-1954 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Pioneers Foundation, Inc.: Publicity, undated (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Pioneers Foundation, Inc.: Minutes of Meetings, 1950-1955 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Pioneers Foundation, Inc.: Reports, 1951-1955 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Pioneers Foundation, Inc.: Financial Records, 1951-1954, 1957 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Pioneers Foundation, Inc.: Clippings, undated (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Pioneers Foundation, Inc.: Various Official Papers; Miscellaneous Materials, undated (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Pioneers Foundation, Inc.: Tape Recordings of Pioneers (Various Notes and Lists), undated (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Pioneers Foundation, Inc.: Lou Blachly - Articles Published in Newspapers, undated (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Pioneers Foundation, Inc.: Clippings and Photographs, undated (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Pioneers Foundation, Inc.: New Mexico Towns - Articles, Clippings, Photographs, undated (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - Pioneers Foundation, Inc.: El Paso, Texas - Clippings from Herald-Post (75th Anniversary Edition), April 28, 1956 (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Pioneers Foundation, Inc.: Lou Blachly - Article on Caesar Brock, The New Mexico Stockman, January 1951 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Pioneers Foundation, Inc.: Lou Blachly - "The Most Unforgettable Character I Ever Met(Manuscript), undated (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Pioneers Foundation, Inc.: Lou Blachly - Caesar Brock (Manuscript), undated (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Pioneers Foundation, Inc.: Caesar and Henry Brock. undated (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Pioneers Foundation, Inc.: E.A. Cunningham. undated (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Pioneers Foundation, Inc.: Charles B. Morrill, undated (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Pioneers Foundation, Inc.: Marvin Powe, undated (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Pioneers Foundation, Inc.: Agnes Snider, undated (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Pioneers Foundation, Inc.: Montague Stevens, undated (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Pioneers Foundation, Inc.: Jack Stockbridge, undated (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - Pioneers Foundation, Inc.: Marietta Wetherill. undated (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - Pioneers Foundation, Inc.: Various Pioneers, undated (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - Pioneers Foundation, Inc.: Montague Stevens - Transcripts of Tape Interviews (Reels 4-72, Incomplete), undated (Box 24)
- Series X: Nature Writings, 1948-1964
  - Correspondence (Angus Cameron of A.A. Knopf), 1960-1964 (Box 25, Folder 1-3)
  - Correspondence (Alan Collins of Curtis Brown), 1961-1965 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence (Sheridan Oman), 1959-1964 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence (Randolph Jenks), 1958-1965 (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence (Tree Guide), 1959-1965 (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Financial Records of Nature Publications, undated (Box 25, Folder 8)